Amanda L. Morris

Englewood, CO linkedin.com/in/amanda-morris-web-development

303.817.7593 amandahenry2@comcast.net

Frontend Web Developer

Over 10 years' experience writing and shaping content optimized for search engines, designing templates for optimal UX, and utilizing responsive web design using multiple CMSs, including WordPress, Drupal, DNN, SharePoint, and Squarespace. Proven ability to juggle production and development tasks through to completion under tight deadlines. Recognized for effective communication skills and increasing project efficiency.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SQL
Content Management Systems: WordPress, DNN, Drupal, SharePoint

Design Tools: Photoshop, Dreamweaver

Version-Control System: Git

Professional Experience

IBM WATSON HEALTH, Greenwood Village, CO

January 2017 – November 2019

Frontend Web Developer

- Transitioned Truven Health and other IBM-acquired web content to IBM Watson Health domain using WordPress, Drupal, and IBM's Provider Workbench, while also maintaining legacy content in DNN. Over 1,500 pages of content were analyzed for effectiveness and then imported to IBM Watson Health sites over a 3-month period.
- Collaborated closely with range of teams to align required functionality, style guidelines, SEO improvement, and platforms, which required regularly developing custom code.
- Streamlined and redirected older content to newer optimized content under IBM domain while retaining search engine benefits.
- Revamped disparate content sources, including product training materials, government, and global audience materials to an updated, consistent template, implementing responsive design for multiple devices.
- Managed web presence for 100 Top Hospitals campaign, a highly publicized national hospital achievement program, including coordinating information from quarterly winner announcements.
- Created forms that incorporated user input validation and provided tips and suggestions for SEO success to collect content for blog articles, product pages, and YouTube videos.
- Adopted and utilized Github version-control system to track updates and changes in production, improving collaboration, enabling restoration of older versions, and providing backup and history on different projects.
- Adopted Kanban process and provided critical feedback to team in migrating to this new process, increasing knowledge sharing and improving collaboration and process efficiency.

TRUVEN HEALTH ANALYTICS, Greenwood Village, CO

2012 - 2017

Web Administrator

- Coordinated and contributed to execution of marketing projects by determining desired results, designing front-end templates for marketing landing and campaign pages, customer training, events, interactive forms, materials, and presentations from tradeshows and recorded webinars.
- Measured success of marketing campaigns with web analytics utilizing different metrics, keying in on end-user desired terms and content adapted to end-user searches.
- Created new HTML/CSS templates with updated branding and style guidelines and enhanced functionality, making content more consistent and user experience a priority.
- Applied global settings for international clients, adapting content to needs of international users.
- Provided continuous usability and visibility improvement of public-facing website by reviewing success of organic search results using Google Analytics, and by making content more visible and immediate for end-users.
- Uploaded and provided captioning for videos on YouTube platform, enhancing visibility of video content.

THOMSON REUTERS, Greenwood Village, CO

2005 - 2012

Web Administrator

- Maintained public-facing website promoting products and services, along with content from experts in healthcare industry.
- Managed company-wide intranet used as resource for employee benefits and events.
- Maintained SQL database of leads and customers seeking supplemental information.
- Evolved public-facing promotional content with secured, confidential content, and implemented forms for customer support and marketing tracking, creating more interactive and compelling content.
- Generated presentations and reports, conducted research, and enhanced colleagues' marketing materials and presentations with pertinent content, providing a marketing focus.

Education / Continuing Education

- Certificate, University of Denver Coding Boot Camp, Anticipated certification September 2020
 - JavaScript; browser-based technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery; MySQL and MongoDB databases; deployment with Heroku and Git; PHP/Laravel; writing tests for quality assurance; and server-side development using Node.js, Express, MERN Stack
- Master of Science (MS), Information and Communication Technology, concentration in Web Design and Development Technologies, University of Denver, Denver, CO
- Bachelor of Arts (BS), English Language and Literature, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO

Professional Development

• **IBM-Sponsored Training**: Emotional Intelligence, Cybersecurity and Privacy, Agile Principles and Methodologies, Bootstrap Tutorials, Working in Teams with Different Culture, Interpersonal Communication that Builds Trust, What Makes a Leader?